A Guide to the Robert and Wilva Breen Collection, 1933-1980
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
The Robert and Wilva Breen Collection 1933-1980
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Breen 001
135 boxes 45 cubic feet (67.5 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated to George Mason University
Biographical Information
In the early 1930s, a small group of arts patrons from Philadelphia and New York began to act upon their conviction that Americans should have a national theater organization that would serve the American public better than Broadway, with its high ticket prices and limited touring policy. Under the leadership of Leopold Stokowski, and with the help of several influential supporters, they persuaded Congress to enact a federal charter for a national theater - a rare and significant authorization but for very few organizations such as the Smithsonian Institution, the Red Cross, and the Federal Reserve Bank. Signed by Franklin Roosevelt on July 3, 1935, the charter of The American National Theatre and Academy (ANTA) called for: A people's project, organized and conducted in their interest, free from commercialism, but with the firm intent of being as far as possible self-supporting. A national theatre should bring to the people throughout the country their heritage of the great drama of the past and the best of the present, which has been too frequently unavailable to them under existing conditions. Action on the new charter stalled for nearly a decade, however, with the creation of the WPA Federal Theatre Project, which provided Depression relief to theater artists from 1935 until 1939, and then the onset of World War II. Perhaps more to the point, the ANTA board, comprised of prominent citizens and business leaders from outside the theater community, could not agree on the goals of ANTA. When the war ended, Robert Breen, a dynamic theater director, actor, and producer fresh out of the Army Air Corps, saw in ANTA the opportunity for his vision of a national theater. He persuaded a fellow veteran, Robert Porterfield, founder of the Barter Theatre in Abingdon, Virginia, to join him in his effort to devise and propose to the ANTA board a plan for a national theater supported by a foundation. In 1946 the ANTA board voted to accept the Breen-Porterfield Foundation Plan and persuaded Robert Breen to serve as executive secretary of ANTA. To provide the organization with necessary expertise, the board was reconstituted to include prestigious theater professionals such as Brooks Atkinson, Cheryl Crawford, Paul Green, Moss Hart, Helen Hayes, Sam Jaffe, and Raymond Massey. Robert Breen and a small, dedicated team comprised mostly of volunteers set furiously to work in his own living quarters above the Hudson Theater on 44th Street. At his side was his co-worker and wife Wilva Davis Breen, who had been instrumental in promoting and guiding the ANTA plan to completion. Together, the two of them had established the Chicago unit of the Federal Theatre Project, an experience which convinced Breen that theater in America was in need of more than a temporary relief program. Thus began a remarkable period in American theater that, with the infusion of ANTA support and energy, saw the revival of the Experimental Theatre in New York, the growth of regional and university theater programs, the encouragement of playwrights and performers, the broadcasting of quality dramatic presentations to millions of Americans on television in its fledgling years, and ground breaking cultural exchanges that warmed a Cold War world. Internationally, ANTA promoted artistic exchanges between the U.S. and Europe and entertainment for American troops serving abroad. It began in 1949 with a U.S. tour of Hamlet throughout Europe, culminating in a performance at Elsinore Castle in Denmark, the actual setting of the play. During the 1950s ANTA sponsored such projects as the American National Ballet Theatre's tour of Europe, and American participation in the Berlin Arts Festival in 1951. Productions showing different sides of life in America were played to European audiences. Among the many were the musicals Oklahoma and Porgy and Bess.
Scope and Content
The Robert Breen Theatre Collection is a primary source from which one may research the early beginnings of government support for the performing arts and the people responsible for them. It details the work of Robert Breen, the driving force behind the reformation of ANTA in 1946 and a staunch supporter of its eventual successor, the National Endowment for the Arts. The Robert Breen Theatre Collection aids in the gaining of a better understanding of the early operations of ANTA. Covering the years 1933-1980, it consists of working papers, correspondence, drafts, news clippings, scripts, photographs and other theatrical materials which document Breen's career with ANTA from 1944 to 1952. The Collection also reflects Breen's personal interests such as television, film, and political causes.
Arrangement
Alphabetic according to folder title
Contents List
- The Robert Breen Collection
  - ANTA BOARD MINUTES FEB 1937 - NOV 1945, Folder 1 (Box Box 1)
  - LOG JUN - AUG. 1946., Folder 2 (Box Box 1)
  - LOG SEPT. - DEC. 1946., Folder 3 (Box Box 1)
  - LOG DEC. 1946., Folder 4 (Box Box 1)
  - ANTA LOG (PHOTOCOPY) JUNE - AUGUST 1946., Folder 5 (Box Box 1)
  - ANTA LOG (COPY) # 2 PLUS # 6 1946., Folder 6 (Box Box 1)
  - ANTA BOARD MINUTES FEB. 1946 - DEC. 1946., Folder 7 (Box Box 1)
  - LOGS 1946 - 1947., Folder 1 (Box Box 2)
  - LOGS 1946 - 1947., Folder 2 (Box Box 2)
  - LOG JAN 1947 EXPERIMENTAL THEATER., Folder 3 (Box Box 2)
  - LOG MARCH 1947., Folder 4 (Box Box 1)
  - MISC BREEN PLUS RECEIPTS AND DISBURSEMENTS., Folder 5 (Box Box 2)
  - ANTA BOARD MINUTES JAN 1947 - DEC 1947., Folder 1 (Box Box 3)
  - LOG APRIL 1947., Folder 2 (Box Box 3)
  - LOG MAY 1947., Folder 3 (Box Box 3)
  - LOG JULY 1947., Folder 4 (Box Box 3)
  - LOG JULY 1947., Folder 5 (Box Box 3)
  - LOG AUGUST 1947., Folder 6 (Box Box 3)
  - LOG NOV. 1947., Folder 1 (Box Box 4)
  - LOG DEC. 1947., Folder 2 (Box Box 4)
  - ANTA BOARD MINUTES FEB. 1947 - MARCH 1948., Folder 3 (Box Box 4)
  - LOG JAN 1948., Folder 4 (Box Box 4)
  - DAILY LOG 1948., Folder 5 (Box Box 4)
  - DAILY LOG 1948., Folder 6 (Box Box 4)
  - WILSON FILM DATA., Folder 1 (Box Box 5)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, OUTGOING IRVING PLACE., Folder 2 (Box Box 5)
  - TO BE DONE CORRESPONDENCE, RECEIVED IRVING PLACE., Folder 3 (Box Box 5)
  - WILSON SCRIPT DATA AND NOTES (OLD)., Folder 4 (Box Box 5)
  - WILSON DATA (OLD) - LETTERS - WILSON FILM., Folder 5 (Box Box 5)
  - WILSON SCRIPT (1ST DRAFT) AND NOTES., Folder 6 (Box Box 5)
  - WILSON SCRIPT 1ST DRAFT ! NOTES., Folder 7 (Box Box 5)
  - SPONSORSHIP CORRESPONDENCE WILSON FILM., Folder 8 (Box Box 5)
  - WILSON SCRIPT., Folder 9 (Box Box 5)
  - WILSON SCRIPT (YELLOW)/ UNKNOWN SOLDIER COPY 5A., Folder 1 (Box Box 6)
  - CLARKE CORRESPONDENCE RE: WILSON FILM., Folder 2 (Box Box 6)
  - LETTERS - SOLDIER FILM., Folder 3 (Box Box 6)
  - WORKING SCRIPT - UNKNOWN SOLDIER., Folder 4 (Box Box 6)
  - MATERIAL - EXCEPTS! CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 5 (Box Box 6)
  - PRESENTATIONAL MATERIAL., Folder 6 (Box Box 6)
  - WAR DEPT., Folder 7 (Box Box 6)
  - OPINION AND SUGGESTION - FILM WW, Folder 8 (Box Box 6)
  - ANTA NOTES ON W SCRIPT, MISC BY DAVIS (THE WOODROW WILSON FOUNDATION)., Folder 9 (Box Box 6)
  - WOODROW WILSON/ BY HOWARD KOCH AND JOHN HUSTON., Folder 10 (Box Box 6)
  - WILSON REVIEWS - ZANUCK. FILM., Folder 11 (Box Box 6)
  - PRE - ANTA CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 12 (Box Box 6)
  - PRE- ANTA., Folder 13 (Box Box 6)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE JUNE 1951., Folder 14 (Box Box 6)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE JULY 1951., Folder 15 (Box Box 6)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE AUGUST 1951., Folder 16 (Box Box 6)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE SEPT. 1951., Folder 17 (Box Box 6)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE JAN. - MARCH 1952., Folder 18 (Box Box 6)
  - FAUST - 1939 - PARTIAL SCRIPT INCOMPLETE., Folder 1 (Box Box 7)
  - "Dr. FAUSTUS" "GHOSTS". AND "ON YOUR TOES" REVIEWS., Folder 2 (Box Box 7)
  - "Dr. FAUSTUS", "GHOSTS", AND "ON YOUR TOES". REVIEWS., Folder 3 (Box Box 7)
  - CRITICAL REVIEWS (OF HAMLET) EXCERPTS., Folder 4 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET EXCERPTS FROM CRITICAL REVIEWS., Folder 5 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET USO., Folder 6 (Box Box 7)
  - ROBERT BREEN / HAMLET., Folder 7 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET 1949., Folder 8 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET ( BARTER 1948 - 49) COMPLETE BUDGET., Folder 9 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET (PARTIAL BARTER ROUTE., Folder 10 (Box Box 7)
  - BLEVINS DAVIS HAMLET., Folder 11 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET 1949 CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 12 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 13 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 14 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET 1949 DANISH HAMLET FESTIVAL., Folder 15 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET MISC NOTES., Folder 16 (Box Box 7)
  - BREEN - "HAMLET" SCRIPT., Folder 17 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET - STAGE NOTES AND KRONBORG GROUND PLAN., Folder 18 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET TOWN EUROPE (1949)., Folder 19 (Box Box 7)
  - HAMLET - TOUR., Folder 1 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET (DEN) TOUR., Folder 2 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET TOUR EUROPE., Folder 3 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET TOUR EUROPE., Folder 4 (Box Box 8)
  - TOUR HOLLAND, OTHER NATIONS (BELGIUM, FRANCE, ITALY ENGLAND) / HAMLET., Folder 5 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET - TOUR - GERMANY., Folder 6 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET VENICE FESTIVAL., Folder 7 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET - CORRESPONDENCE 1949 - 1952., Folder 8 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET CORRESPONDENCE 1949 - 52., Folder 9 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET 1949 CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 10 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET - GERMAN TOURIST INFORMATION., Folder 11 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET YUGOSLAVIA., Folder 12 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET - BIO GRAPHICS., Folder 13 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET BREEN NOTES FROM NOTEBOOK., Folder 14 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET (BIOGRAPHIES AND RESUMES OF ARTISTS)., Folder 15 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET ROEBLING PIX., Folder 16 (Box Box 8)
  - HAMLET TREATMENT FOR A FILM BY ROBERT BREEN., Folder 1 (Box Box 9)
  - HAMLET - BOOKLETS., Folder 2 (Box Box 9)
  - HAMLET STENCIL., Folder 3 (Box Box 9)
  - HAMLET ETC. - 1949, NEWSPAPER CLIPS, DAVIS, KRONBORG CASTLE ELSINORE - HAMLET FESTIVAL., Folder 4 (Box Box 9)
  - HAMLET NEWS CLIPS MISC., Folder 5 (Box Box 9)
  - ACTORS EQUITY - ECONOMIC BETTERMENT COMMITTEE., Folder 1 (Box Box 10)
  - R. B. CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 2 (Box Box 10)
  - BREEN'S NOTEBOOK., Folder 3 (Box Box 10)
  - ANTA MATERIAL THEATRE, THEATER (Box Box 10)
  - NATIONAL THEATER CONFERENCE TALK., Folder 5 (Box Box 10)
  - AETA SPEECH DRATT AND REVISIONS., Folder 6 (Box Box 10)
  - BREEN STATEMENT - RECIPIENTS., Folder 7 (Box Box 10)
  - BRAOZDA, DALIBAR., Folder 8 (Box Box 10)
  - EARLY ANTA FROM - III AIMS AND OBJECTIVES INTRODUCTION SUMMERY., Folder 9 (Box Box 10)
  - BREEN RESIGNATION., Folder 10 (Box Box 10)
  - BREEN RESIGNATION NEWSPRINT (2 "VARIETY" ARTICLES; MULTIPLE COPIES; JUNE 1951)., Folder 11 (Box Box 10)
  - REASONS FOR RESIGNATION AS EXEC. SECRETARY., Folder 12 (Box Box 10)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 13 (Box Box 10)
  - H. HAYES 1951., Folder 14 (Box Box 10)
  - VARIETY WED, JUNE 13, 1951., Folder 15 (Box Box 10)
  - "REORG. OF ANTA" TO AMER. ED. THEATER ASSOC., Folder 16 (Box Box 10)
  - TELEGRAM RE: R. STEVENS ON R. BREEN (MULTIPLE COPIES)., Folder 17 (Box Box 10)
  - AETA SPEECH PUBLICITY., Folder 18 (Box Box 10)
  - RESIGNATION LETTER., Folder 19 (Box Box 10)
  - EXCHANGE OF PERSONS - OUTGOING DOWLING, ROBERT - 1951., Folder 1 (Box Box 11)
  - CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 2 (Box Box 11)
  - EXECUTIVE SECRETARY CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 3 (Box Box 11)
  - INTERNATIONAL BARRAULT., Folder 4 (Box Box 11)
  - INTERNATIONAL DLD VIC., Folder 5 (Box Box 11)
  - FILM IDEAS, LETTERS, MISC., Folder 6 (Box Box 11)
  - FILM IDEAS, LETTERS, MISC., Folder 7 (Box Box 11)
  - GREEN NATIONAL THEATER TOUR., Folder 8 (Box Box 11)
  - GREEN NATIONAL THEATER TOUR., Folder 9 (Box Box 11)
  - MERCER, JOHNNY., Folder 10 (Box Box 11)
  - NEWMAN, DANNY., Folder 11 (Box Box 11)
  - FRENCH, MARY STEWART., Folder 12 (Box Box 11)
  - PORTERFIELD, ROBERT., Folder 13 (Box Box 11)
  - ARLEN (SPECIAL) VARIOUS - LISTS OF ARLEN SONGS., Folder 1 (Box Box 12)
  - PHOTO - ORIGIN IN PHOTO FILE., Folder 2 (Box Box 12)
  - CANDIDO., Folder 3 (Box Box 12)
  - A DRAM OF POISON (FILM)., Folder 4 (Box Box 12)
  - "CHASE OWES W. AND R.B" BLUES - OPERA., Folder 5 (Box Box 12)
  - FREE AND EASY LIM PARTNERSHIP PAPERS., Folder 6 (Box Box 12)
  - FARROW, PETER 1960 - 66., Folder 7 (Box Box 12)
  - FILM IDEAS - LETTERS, MISC., Folder 8 (Box Box 12)
  - FREE AND EASY (ARLEN)., Folder 9 (Box Box 12)
  - BUTTON - BUTTON., Folder 10 (Box Box 12)
  - FAREWELL TO FEAR (FILM)., Folder 11 (Box Box 12)
  - HOUSE OF FLOWERS., Folder 12 (Box Box 12)
  - FRINK, CHARLES., Folder 13 (Box Box 12)
  - DAVIS, WRAY., Folder 1 (Box Box 13)
  - DAVIS, WRAY., Folder 2 (Box Box 13)
  - FILM IDEAS, LETTERS, MISC., Folder 3 (Box Box 13)
  - HARDWICKE, CEDRIC., Folder 4 (Box Box 13)
  - STEWART, FRED (PLAYWRIGHT) 1962, LOW BUDGET FILM., Folder 5 (Box Box 13)
  - "TEN GIRLS AGO"., Folder 6 (Box Box 13)
  - DOWLING, EDDIE ('64)., Folder 7 (Box Box 13)
  - MURPHY, PATRICK., Folder 8 (Box Box 13)
  - BOOK REVIEWS 1965., Folder 9 (Box Box 13)
  - PHOTO - ORIGIN PHOTO FILE., Folder 10 (Box Box 13)
  - HALLMARK TV., Folder 11 (Box Box 13)
  - ARLEN, HAROLD (PHOTO) REVIEWS AND TV PROPOSALS., Folder 1 (Box Box 14)
  - ARLEN, HAROLD REVIEWS AND TV PROPOSALS., Folder 2 (Box Box 14)
  - CAPOTE, TRUMAN., Folder 3 (Box Box 14)
  - KAUFFMANN, STANLEY., Folder 4 (Box Box 14)
  - HARE, MONTY., Folder 5 (Box Box 14)
  - HARRITY, RICHARD., Folder 6 (Box Box 14)
  - KERZ, LEO., Folder 7 (Box Box 14)
  - HUISMAN, MAURICE 1966 - 73., Folder 8 (Box Box 14)
  - HUISMAN, MAURICE 1966 - 73., Folder 9 (Box Box 14)
  - POST - ANTA 1960s AND 70s., Folder 10 (Box Box 14)
  - CONN, UNIV OF, Folder 11 (Box Box 14)
  - BONFILS, HELEN., Folder 12 (Box Box 14)
  - JOHN, MARY W. Dr., Folder 12 (Box Box 14)
  - MISS HARGREAVES NOVEL - COPIES FROM ORIGINAL BOOKS., Folder 1 (Box Box 18)
  - SENARIO JESSE., Folder 2 (Box Box 18)
  - NEW MOVIES ON NEWSPAPERS 1962., Folder 3 (Box Box 18)
  - PERSONAL LETTERS., Folder 4 (Box Box 18)
  - "ANGLES", LISTINGS., Folder 5 (Box Box 18)
  - CASSETTEE VENDING MACHINE., Folder 6 (Box Box 18)
  - FAUST FILM 1964., Folder 7 (Box Box 18)
  - 16MM - EXHIB., Folder 8 (Box Box 18)
  - FACES 16MM - NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS., Folder 9 (Box Box 18)
  - " BROTHER GO"., Folder 10 (Box Box 18)
  - NEWSPAPER CUTTINGS - FILM., Folder 11 (Box Box 18)
  - PUTNEY SWOPE - FROM NEWS PAPER., Folder 12 (Box Box 18)
  - REVIEWS - MINOR - FROM NEWSPAPERS., Folder 13 (Box Box 18)
  - GOING PUBLIC., Folder 14 (Box Box 18)
  - (REVIEWS) - GENRE., Folder 15 (Box Box 18)
  - REVOLUTION IN MODERN ART., Folder 1 (Box Box 19)
  - EASY RIDER., Folder 2 (Box Box 19)
  - GREETINGS - CUTTINGS FROM NEWSPAPERS., Folder 3 (Box Box 19)
  - OUT OF IT - NEWSPAPER CUTTING., Folder 4 (Box Box 19)
  - TREE - 1969 - FROM NEWSPAPERS., Folder 5 (Box Box 19)
  - WEDDING PARTY - NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS., Folder 6 (Box Box 19)
  - PROPOSAL - SAMPLES., Folder 7 (Box Box 19)
  - WOODSTOCK (16MM) NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS., Folder 8 (Box Box 19)
  - FINANCE PROSPECTS / BRO GO., Folder 9 (Box Box 19)
  - FILMING FILE 1969 - 71SOME LATE 1950s / PRODUCTION OF BROTHERS GO BY INFO FILMS., Folder 10 (Box Box 19)
  - FILMING FILE 1969 - 71 (SOME LATE 1950s)., Folder 11 (Box Box 19)
  - FILMING FILE / 1969 - 1971 / SOME LATE 1950s., Folder 12 (Box Box 19)
  - FILMING FILE / 1969 - 71 / SOME LATE 1950s / PRODUCTION OF BROTHER GO BY INFO FILMS., Folder 13 (Box Box 19)
  - FILMING FILE / 1969 - 71 / SOME LATE 1950s., Folder 14 (Box Box 19)
  - ROBERT MILLER OCT 69 FEB. 71., Folder 1 (Box Box 20)
  - FILM EARLY 1970s., Folder 2 (Box Box 20)
  - CRUCIBLE, INC. (T.I.P.)., Folder 3 (Box Box 20)
  - DIRECTORS INFO CRUCIBLE PROJECTS., Folder 4 (Box Box 20)
  - THE GREENING OF AMERICA - CLIPPINGS., Folder 5 (Box Box 20)
  - REVIEW., Folder 6 (Box Box 20)
  - WRITERS INFO - SCRIPTS - CRUCIBLE PROJECTS., Folder 7 (Box Box 20)
  - 1970 - 73 MISC. NEWS CLIPPINGS AND NOTES., Folder 8 (Box Box 20)
  - ACTORS INFO - CRUCIBLE PROJECTS., Folder 9 (Box Box 20)
  - BOOKS TO ORDER., Folder 10 (Box Box 20)
  - POSSIBLE PROJECTS CRUCIBLE., Folder 11 (Box Box 20)
  - FOLIO - FILM PROJECTS., Folder 12 (Box Box 20)
  - "CRUCIBLE" (GEN.)., Folder 13 (Box Box 20)
  - FINANCE CRUCIBLE POSSIBLE CO - OP PROJECTS., Folder 14 (Box Box 20)
  - H. KLINE'S "REVOLUTION IN MODERN ART"., Folder 15 (Box Box 20)
  - FILMAKERS CRUCIBLE INTERESTING PROJECTS., Folder 16 (Box Box 20)
  - CRUCIBLE MEMO JUNE 71 / ALSO "KEY" SHEET JUNE 72., Folder 17 (Box Box 20)
  - "FANTASTIC FARAGO" NEWS CLIPS 1971., Folder 18 (Box Box 20)
  - FOLIO (ADDITIONS AND CHANGES)., Folder 19 (Box Box 20)
  - FOXES - KERZ FROM DEC. 1, 1971., Folder 20 (Box Box 20)
  - KERZ ("FOXES") FROM JULY 6 - T0 NOV. 30 - 1971., Folder 1 (Box Box 21)
  - PORTLAND - HINDE, Ltd. GOSS., Folder 2 (Box Box 21)
  - "STEPPERFOLF"/H. HESSE. INVESTMENT OPPORTUNITY PROPOSAL., Folder 3 (Box Box 21)
  - REVOLUTION., Folder 4 (Box Box 21)
  - CABLE TV., Folder 5 (Box Box 21)
  - R. MILLER FROM FEB. 1971., Folder 6 (Box Box 21)
  - MISC. NEWS CLIPPINGS., Folder 7 (Box Box 21)
  - ASSASSINS., Folder 1 (Box Box 22)
  - ASSASSINS., Folder 2 (Box Box 22)
  - GERARD RE CRUCIBLE 5 JUNE 1972., Folder 3 (Box Box 22)
  - H. KLINE (ART) / NOV 72 / SCREENINGS., Folder 4 (Box Box 22)
  - HOLDEN, HILARY / (ASSASSINS)., Folder 5 (Box Box 22)
  - KLINE, HERB "WIDOW MAKER"., Folder 6 (Box Box 22)
  - LESLEY, TOM - 1972., Folder 7 (Box Box 22)
  - LIFE VOL. 23 NO. 23, JUNE 16., Folder 8 (Box Box 22)
  - PEACHIE LENIC., Folder 9 (Box Box 22)
  - REVOLUTION MEMO BBC 13 JUNE 72., Folder 10 (Box Box 22)
  - "TRICKS" (JULY 72)., Folder 11 (Box Box 22)
  - TRICKS., Folder 12 (Box Box 22)
  - MISC., Folder 13 (Box Box 22)
  - MISC. (NY PARKS, BROWNSTONES)., Folder 14 (Box Box 22)
  - ASSASSIN - BUDGET., Folder 15 (Box Box 22)
  - MEDICINE, ILLNESSES., Folder 16 (Box Box 22)
  - NEWS CLIPPINGS., Folder 1 (Box Box 23)
  - ANNUAL REPORT 1973., Folder 2 (Box Box 23)
  - ARTICLE AS SCENES. VILLAGE VOICE SEPT. 6-12-1973., Folder 3 (Box Box 23)
  - CORRESPONDENCE AND MISC., Folder 4 (Box Box 23)
  - FILM 73 (NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS)., Folder 5 (Box Box 23)
  - FILM - MISC 1973 NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS., Folder 6 (Box Box 23)
  - GENERAL INFO. 1973., Folder 7 (Box Box 23)
  - HERBERT KLINE PLUS TABS JUNE, 1973., Folder 8 (Box Box 23)
  - INFO FILE / SOME NEWS PAPER CLIPPINGS., Folder 9 (Box Box 23)
  - PAINE, TOM., Folder 10 (Box Box 23)
  - MISC. CORRESPONDENCE, Folder 11 (Box Box 23)
  - PAULINE KAEL., Folder 12 (Box Box 23)
  - FILM "TREIVDS" / CONTENT / QUESTIONS., Folder 13 (Box Box 23)
  - PIPER., Folder 14 (Box Box 23)
  - PIPER., Folder 1 (Box Box 24)
  - REVOLUTION '76 CRUCIBLE., Folder 2 (Box Box 24)
  - MISC. CLIPPINGS 1977., Folder 3 (Box Box 24)
  - WASHINGTON INTERNATIONAL ARTS LETTER., Folder 4 (Box Box 24)
  - FILM CLIPS LATE 1970., Folder 5 (Box Box 24)
  - MISC. NEWS CLIPPINGS., Folder 6 (Box Box 24)
  - FILM SCRIPT UNTITLED - BREEN., Folder 7 (Box Box 24)
  - TRICKS., Folder 8 (Box Box 24)
  - DAVIS, WILVA - DENTAL HEALTH., Folder 9 (Box Box 24)
  - WILVA (SEARCHING EMPLOYMENT)., Folder 10 (Box Box 24)
  - DAVIS, WILVA - CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 11 (Box Box 24)
  - WILVA AND CHARLES LOWE - CORRESPONDENCE., Folder 12 (Box Box 24)
  - LETTER TO WILVA DAVIS FROM MARABELL SMITH., Folder 13 (Box Box 24)
  - WILVA DEVIS AND MISC., Folder 14 (Box Box 24)
  - WILVA BREEN., Folder 15 (Box Box 24)
  - BREEN - URFAUST., Folder 1 (Box Box 25)
  - RADIO - TELEVISION 1944., Folder 2 (Box Box 25)
  - TELEVISION SEMINAR (RADIO EXECUTIVES CLUB OF NY) 1944., Folder 3 (Box Box 25)
  - EXCERPTS FROM ARTICLES IN AMERICAN PUBLICATIONS TOWARD A NATIONAL THEATER BY PORTFIELD AND BREEN., Folder 4 (Box Box 25)
  - MISC. LETTERS LISTS OF CONTACT, CHICAGO 1945 - 50., Folder 5 (Box Box 25)
  - ANTA - MISCELLANY BEFORE '51., Folder 6 (Box Box 25)
  - ANTA (GRADUATE ACADEMY PLANS)., Folder 7 (Box Box 25)
  - THE GRADUATE ACADEMY, PLAN BY FORESTC. HARING., Folder 8 (Box Box 25)
  - GRADUATE ACADEMY PLAN., Folder 9 (Box Box 25)
  - ANTA - BREEN WAGNER LETTERS - RE: PLAN TO OPEN A CO-OPERATIVE THEATER GROUP., Folder 10 (Box Box 25)
  - ANTA - GENERAL., Folder 11 (Box Box 25)
  - LETTER TO ANTA INCORPORATORS BY ROBERT PORTER FIELD., Folder 12 (Box Box 25)
  - MISCELLANEOUS - 1946., Folder 13 (Box Box 25)
  - MISCELLANEOUS - 1946., Folder 14 (Box Box 25)
  - NATIONAL THEATER FUND 1946., Folder 15 (Box Box 25)
  - NEWS CLIPPINGS 1948., Folder 16 (Box Box 25)
  - GLASS MENAGERIE 1948 MAILING LIST., Folder 17 (Box Box 25)
  - INSIDE ANTA: SURVEYING THE RESULTS ON FUTURE AIMS BY MASS HART., Folder 18 (Box Box 25)
  - A.E.T.A. MEMBERSHIP AND NEWS., Folder 19 (Box Box 25)
  - MISC. INFO., Folder 20 (Box Box 25)
  - MISC., Folder 1 (Box Box 26)
  - MARTHA GRAHAM TOUR., Folder 2 (Box Box 26)
  - ANTA - EXPERIMENTAL THEATER CHILDREN THEATER BRIEF REORGANIZATION., Folder 3 (Box Box 26)
  - MISC. INFO., Folder 4 (Box Box 26)
  - "THEATER USA", EXCERPTS FROM THEATER ARTS ANTA - ALLIAN., Folder 5 (Box Box 26)
  - PUBLIC RELATIONS., Folder 6 (Box Box 26)
  - THE AMERICAN HERITAGE FOUNDATION: GOOD CITIZENSHIP MATERIALS, Folder 7 (Box Box 26)
  - COLUMBIA LECTURE BUREAU., Folder 8 (Box Box 26)
  - COUNCIL ON THE LIVING THEATER., Folder 9 (Box Box 26)
  - MEMBERSHIP LETTERS., Folder 10 (Box Box 26)
  - ANTA - MISC. 1949 - 1951., Folder 11 (Box Box 26)
  - M. WEBSTER SHAKESPEARE CO. TOUR 1950., Folder 1 (Box Box 27)
  - "NEW LIFE IN THE THEATER" NEW YORK HERALD TRIBUNE 4/3/50., Folder 2 (Box Box 27)
  - ANTA 1951., Folder 3 (Box Box 27)
  - BLANCHE YURKA - REVIEW OF HER ONE - WOMEN SHOW., Folder 4 (Box Box 27)
  - NEWSLETTER CRITICAL DIGEST AND CAST, THEATRICAL PUBLICATIONS 1951., Folder 5 (Box Box 27)
  - NON - ANTA PRODUCTION OF "BILLY BUDD" 1951., Folder 6 (Box Box 27)
  - WILLIAM C. WHITNEY FOUNDATION AND MISC. PAPER CLIPPINGS., Folder 7 (Box Box 26)
  - BURR AND BODEC LAW SUIT., Folder 8 (Box Box 27)
  - SAWYER FALK., Folder 9 (Box Box 27)
  - ST. JAMES THEATER: PLAY BILL THE NATIONAL MAGAZINE EXHIBITION LIST OF ARTS AT CHELSEA NAIONAL BANK., Folder 10 (Box Box 27)
  - CURRENT AND CONTINUING ASSIGNMENTS / PROGRAMS., Folder 11 (Box Box 27)
  - MISC. INFO. LIST OF LIBRARIES (NO DATE)., Folder 12 (Box Box 27)
  - MISC. INFO., Folder 13 (Box Box 27)
  - MISC. INFORMATION., Folder 14 (Box Box 27)
  - MISC., Folder 15 (Box Box 27)
  - ROUTING - BOOKING - TERMS., Folder 16 (Box Box 27)
  - BOARD MEETING., Folder 1 (Box Box 28)
  - A LETTER FROM MARGARET WEBSTER TO R. BREEN REGARDING THE ANTA MEETING., Folder 2 (Box Box 28)
  - ARTICLES REPRESENTATIVES ASSOCIATION, BY - LAWS NOV. 10, 1947., Folder 3 (Box Box 28)
  - REPORTS OF THE ANTA SEMINAR COMMITTEE TO THE BOARD., Folder 4 (Box Box 28)
  - ANTA POLICIES AND MINUTES., Folder 5 (Box Box 28)
  - MINUTES THEATER COMMITTEE MEETINGS (MARCH 7 - SEPT. 15)., Folder 6 (Box Box 28)
  - ANTA - BASIC BUSINESS., Folder 7 (Box Box 28)
  - ENTERTAINMENT / TAXES., Folder 8 (Box Box 28)
  - REVISION OF BY - LAWS 1951., Folder 9 (Box Box 28)
  - ANTA - SHOWTIME., Folder 10 (Box Box 28)
  - ADDRESSOGRAPH., Folder 11 (Box Box 28)
  - US GOVT. TAX (ADM. LEGISL)., Folder 12 (Box Box 28)
  - US GOVT TAX (ADM. LEGISL.)., Folder 13 (Box Box 28)
  - ANTA - BOARD OF DIRECTORS., Folder 14 (Box Box 28)
  - FUND RAISING 1946., Folder 1 (Box Box 29)
  - MONTHLY REPORTS OCT 1948 - MAY 1949., Folder 2 (Box Box 29)
  - ORGANIZATION, MEMB., Folder 3 (Box Box 29)
  - LETTER FROM DOROTHY VAN KIRK, RE: MINUTES OF THE MARCH 14TH MEETING TO M.R. MILLENSON, WASH. D.C., Folder 4 (Box Box 29)